<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Smeden I Sund ]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Smeden I Sund ]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/sund-fiskerimuseum-smeden-i-sund/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 13:02:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/sund-fiskerimuseum-smeden-i-sund/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 13:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img alt="Smeden i Sund. 7.3K likes. Kunst smie Sund fiskerimuseum" src="https://scontent-iad3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-1/p200x200/26814732_1681816525172619_6358619518223265240_n.jpg?oh=3f4355ca9c945fb736acd05ad407c037&oe=5B19D9C0">]]></description>
            <link>https://www.facebook.com/SmedeniSund/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4f1006bb-6be7-4d6a-9173-55abc49f7be2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 13:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is this about ?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/7284e2f1897fde69460ccc94f4ecc2e0/croprotate.jpg?cropheight=3956&cropwidth=5548&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F6de9b582-bed2-4ff7-99c1-f6a7126bfce5.jpg&x=0&y=0">,<h1>What is this about ?</h1>,<p>It’s almost an fairy-tail and then on the other hand it’s not, it is a story about life happens and what you make it to be. Are you ready for the in depth perspective to one of the oldest tourist attractions in Lofoten?</p>,<p>Smeden I Sund (Blacksmith of Sund) started out as an traditional blacksmith of that time, in 1947 Hans Gjertsen founded the smithy in Sund and offered he’s services to the local fishermen. Of that day and standard he was an educated man fresh out of an internship in Kabelvåg where the regional center of industrial development was. Lofoten as an region at that time was a poor region on average, The local fish dealers or more commonly known as the “islands kings” of that time. They did control commodity, trade and goods along the price of the fish and export. The local fishermen was slave bound to there kings in an endless loop of credit and dept. Among the fishermen there where next to nothing of liquid cash so running the smithy meant giving credit hoping they where able to pay up at the end of fishing season. Living like this at that point in time when the industrial boom swept over the rest of the world, slowly Hans Gjertsen found him self and he’s line of work in less and less demand, the standardization of parts paved way for the mechanic. This is the crucial moment of choice life lead up too for Hans Gjertsen. This story and more makes out the Sund Fiskerimuseum today, Founded and with grand opening in 1964 the museum and it’s smithy is still active in the same fashion as Hans Gjertsen developed he’s pioneering adventure in to tourism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sund-fiskerimuseum-smeden-i-sund/what-is-this-about/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3636a548-0b3b-4e3a-bd58-9904bfde7f9b</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 11:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>